Arizona Water Resources Committee Collection, 1955-1992
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Arizona Water Resources Committee Collection 1955-1992
MS 430
Arizona Water Resources Committee
Papers, 1955-1992, bulk 1960-1990. This collection is comprised of the papers of Arizona Water Resources Committee (AWRC). Items include business and research files. The bulk of the material consists of business records including meeting agenda/notices and minutes, correspondence, plans, reports and publications, relating to various projects and programs from AWRC.
2 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
None.
Biographical Note
The Arizona Water Resources Committee (AWRC), was a political interest group that had significant impact upon the formulation and implementation of water policy and water research programs in Arizona from 1956 (the year is was created) through the mid 1990’s. The committee sought to increase the water yield from Arizona's watersheds through vegetative manipulation and modification. It was the principal sponsor and supporter of the Arizona Watershed Program, a network of research, action, and public relations and information projects designed to achieve the goal of increased water supplies for the state.
Organization
This Collections is organized into 2 series.
Series I: Organization 1955-1992
Series II: Research 1955-1992
Papers, 1955-1992, bulk 1960-1990. This collection is comprised of the papers of Arizona Water Resources Committee (AWRC). Arizona Water Resources Committee (AWRC) Collection has been divided into two series: Organization and Research. The materials related to, created or published by AWRC or members of committee are arranged in the series of the Organization. The materials obtained by AWRC for the purposes of research are arranged in the series of the Research.
The Organization series includes; business correspondence of the AWRC, meeting agendas/notices and meeting minutes, field trip information and related photographs and committee financial information. As well as AWRC directory/roster of members, publications and reports published by the committee. There is also information on the annual symposium sponsored by the committee.
The Research series contains research related materials, not published by the committee, including; the Central Arizona Project (CAP) and the plans for the opening celebration ceremony, water legislation, water related newspaper articles and newsletters, planning proposals and prospectus.
Arizona Water Resource Committee; Central Arizona Project; Water rights; Water conservation; Water-supply; Groundwater--Arizona; Water resources development--Arizona--History; Water--Law and legislation--Arizona; Water resources development--Law and legislation--Arizona; Water quality management--Arziona
- Series 1: Organization, 1956-1992
  This series is arranged alphabetically. It contains business correspondence of Arizona Water Resources Committee, meeting agenda/notice and meeting minutes, field trip information and related photographs, committee’s financial information, history, roster, report and symposium.
  - Organization: Correspondence1956-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Organization: Correspondence1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Organization: Correspondence1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Organization: Correspondence1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Organization: Correspondence1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Organization: Correspondence1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Organization: Field trip1970-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Organization: Financial.1963-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Organization: AWRC history1963-1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Organization: AWRC history – Hanna J. Cortner Report1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Organization: Meeting agenda/notice and minutes. 1957-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Organization: Meeting agenda/notice and minutes. 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Organization: Meeting agenda/notice and minutes 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Organization: Meeting agenda/notice and minutes 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Organization: Roster 1959-1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Organization: Symposium 1959-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Organization: Symposium 1984-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series II: Research, 1955-1992
  This series is arranged alphabetically by folders’ name. It contains research related materials including Central Arizona Project (CAP) and its celebration ceremony stuff, legislation, newspaper articles and newsletters, planning, proposal and prospectus, presentation, program, project, published papers and reports.
  - Research: Central Arizona Project (CAP)1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Research: Central Arizona Project (CAP) celebration ceremony1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Research: Legislation1956-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Research: Newspaper articles and newsletters. 1956-1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Research: Planning, proposal, prospectus1971-1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Research: Presentation1956-1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Research: Program, projects1956-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Research: Published papers1955-1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Research: Report1956-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Research: Report1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Research: Report1978-1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)